<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Buhler on कल्पान्तरे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/smRtiH/manuH/buhler/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Buhler on कल्पान्तरे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/smRtiH/manuH/buhler/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/smRtiH/manuH/buhler/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/smRtiH/manuH/buhler/01/</guid>
      <description>001	The great sages approached Manu, who was seated with a collected mind, and, having duly worshipped him, spoke as follows: 002	&amp;lsquo;Deign, divine one, to declare to us precisely and in due order the sacred laws of each of the (four chief) castes (varna) and of the intermediate ones. 003	&amp;lsquo;For thou, O Lord, alone knowest the purport, (i.e.) the rites, and the knowledge of the soul, (taught) in this whole ordinance of the Self-existent (Svayambhu), which is unknowable and unfathomable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/smRtiH/manuH/buhler/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/smRtiH/manuH/buhler/02/</guid>
      <description>001	Learn that sacred law which is followed by men learned (in the Veda) and assented to in their hearts by the virtuous, who are ever exempt from hatred and inordinate affection. 002	To act solely from a desire for rewards is not laudable, yet an exemption from that desire is not (to be found) in this (world): for on (that) desire is grounded the study of the Veda and the performance of the actions, prescribed by the Veda.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/smRtiH/manuH/buhler/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/smRtiH/manuH/buhler/03/</guid>
      <description>001	The vow (of studying) the three Vedas under a teacher must be kept for thirty-six years, or for half that time, or for a quarter, or until the (student) has perfectly learnt them. 002	(A student) who has studied in due order the three Vedas, or two, or even one only, without breaking the (rules of) studentship, shall enter the order of householders. 003	He who is famous for (the strict performance of) his duties and has received his heritage, the Veda, from his father, shall be honoured, sitting on a couch and adorned with a garland, with (the present of) a cow (and the honey-mixture).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/smRtiH/manuH/buhler/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/smRtiH/manuH/buhler/04/</guid>
      <description>001	Having dwelt with a teacher during the fourth part of (a man&amp;rsquo;s) life, a Brahmana shall live during the second quarter (of his existence) in his house, after he has wedded a wife. 002	A Brahmana must seek a means of subsistence which either causes no, or at least little pain (to others), and live (by that) except in times of distress. 003	For the purpose of gaining bare subsistence, let him accumulate property by (following those) irreproachable occupations (which are prescribed for) his (caste), without (unduly) fatiguing his body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/smRtiH/manuH/buhler/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/smRtiH/manuH/buhler/05/</guid>
      <description>001	The sages, having heard the duties of a Snataka thus declared, spoke to great-souled Bhrigu, who sprang from fire: 002	&amp;lsquo;How can Death have power over Brahmanas who know the sacred science, the Veda, (and) who fulfil their duties as they have been explained (by thee), O Lord? &#39; 003	Righteous Bhrigu, the son of Manu, (thus) answered the great sages: &amp;lsquo;Hear, (in punishment) of what faults Death seeks to shorten the lives of Brahmanas!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/smRtiH/manuH/buhler/06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/smRtiH/manuH/buhler/06/</guid>
      <description>001	A twice-born Snataka, who has thus lived according to the law in the order of householders, may, taking a firm resolution and keeping his organs in subjection, dwell in the forest, duly (observing the rules given below). 002	When a householder sees his (skin) wrinkled, and (his hair) white, and. the sons of his sons, then he may resort to the forest. 003	Abandoning all food raised by cultivation, and all his belongings, he may depart into the forest, either committing his wife to his sons, or accompanied by her.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/smRtiH/manuH/buhler/07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/smRtiH/manuH/buhler/07/</guid>
      <description>001	I will declare the duties of kings, (and) show how a king should conduct himself, how he was created, and how (he can obtain) highest success. 002	A Kshatriya, who has received according to the rule the sacrament prescribed by the Veda, must duly protect this whole (world). 003	For, when these creatures, being without a king, through fear dispersed in all directions, the Lord created a king for the protection of this whole (creation), 004	Taking (for that purpose) eternal particles of Indra, of the Wind, of Yama, of the Sun, of Fire, of Varuna, of the Moon, and of the Lord of wealth (Kubera).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/smRtiH/manuH/buhler/08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/smRtiH/manuH/buhler/08/</guid>
      <description>001	A king, desirous of investigating law cases, must enter his court of justice, preserving a dignified demeanour, together with Brahmanas and with experienced councillors. 002	There, either seated or standing, raising his right arm, without ostentation in his dress and ornaments, let him examine the business of suitors, 003	Daily (deciding) one after another (all cases) which fall under the eighteen titles (of the law) according to principles drawn from local usages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/smRtiH/manuH/buhler/09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/smRtiH/manuH/buhler/09/</guid>
      <description>001	I will now propound the eternal laws for a husband and his wife who keep to the path of duty, whether they be united or separated. 002	Day and night woman must be kept in dependence by the males (of) their (families), and, if they attach themselves to sensual enjoyments, they must be kept under one&amp;rsquo;s control. 003	Her father protects (her) in childhood, her husband protects (her) in youth, and her sons protect (her) in old age; a woman is never fit for independence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/smRtiH/manuH/buhler/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/smRtiH/manuH/buhler/10/</guid>
      <description>001	Let the three twice-born castes (varna), discharging their (prescribed) duties, study (the Veda); but among them the Brahmana (alone) shall teach it, not the other two; that is an established rule. 002	The Brahmana must know the means of subsistence (prescribed) by law for all, instruct the others, and himself live according to (the law) 003	On account of his pre-eminence, on account of the superiority of his origin, on account of his observance of (particular) restrictive rules, and on account of his particular sanctification the Brahmana is the lord of (all) castes (varna).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/smRtiH/manuH/buhler/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/smRtiH/manuH/buhler/11/</guid>
      <description>001	Him who wishes (to marry for the sake of having) offspring, him who wishes to perform a sacrifice, a traveller, him who has given away all his property, him who begs for the sake of his teacher, his father, or his mother, a student of the Veda, and a sick man, 002	These nine Brahmanas one should consider as Snatakas, begging in order to fulfil the sacred law; to such poor men gifts must be given in proportion to their learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/smRtiH/manuH/buhler/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/kalpAntaram/smRtiH/manuH/buhler/12/</guid>
      <description>001	&amp;lsquo;O sinless One, the whole sacred law, (applicable) to the four castes, has been declared by thee; communicate to us (now), according to the truth, the ultimate retribution for (their) deeds.&amp;rsquo; 002	To the great sages (who addressed him thus) righteous Bhrigu, sprung from Manu, answered, &amp;lsquo;Hear the decision concerning this whole connexion with actions.&amp;rsquo; 003	Action, which springs from the mind, from speech, and from the body, produces either good or evil results; by action are caused the (various) conditions of men, the highest, the middling, and the lowest.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
